Joe Aguado

Web Develo1`per

Bilingual Web Developer with a background in Financial Advisor Services and Business

industry build standards. I aspire to

projects that others can learn from.

In 2016 I built my first weather API

app using Ruby on Rails. I started

Typescript by making a full-stack

deployed application using the

Next.js framework.

making my first HTML websites in

2004. My short term goal is to learn

Administration Management.

I strive to make meaningful, deployable projects that follow

write code and contribute to

Location: North Dallas, Texas Phone: (808) 979-5367

Email: aguado.joe@gmail.com

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/joe-aguado-3a455311b/

Portfolio: www.joeoverflowcode.github.io/ Github: www.github.com/joeoverflowcode

Aora / In Progress - Full Stack Video Sharing App **PROJECTS**

Tech: React Native, Native Wind, Appwrite

Repository: https://github.com/joeoverflowcode/aora

Promptopia / April 2024 - Full Stack create/read/update/destroy App Tech: Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Google OAuth, Mongoose, MongoDB, Vercel

Live: https://deploy-vercel-promptopia.vercel.app/

Repository: https://github.com/ioeoverflowcode/deploy_vercel_promptopia

Texas Coding Club / March 2024 - Front-End Deployed Blog

Tech: React, Tailwind CSS, Figma, Canva, DreamHost

Live:www.texascodingclub.com

Repository: https://github.com/XINEXPORT/vite-ghpages

Bio Behavioral Institute / February 2024 - Front-End MVP Landing

Tech: React, Tailwind, Canva, DreamHost

Live: www.porterprotokeg.com

Repository: https://github.com/joeoverflowcode/bio_behavioral_institute

SKILLS

Most of my recent experience is around the React.js Library and Frameworks. My short term goal is learn and implement Typescript in a full stack project

Languages: Javascript, Java, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Next.js, React Native, Express, Bootstrap

Database: MongoDB, Appwrite, PostgreSQL

Software: Git, Github, Excel, Microsoft Office, Ximple, Bloomberg Terminal, Slack

Deployment: Github Pages, DreamHost, Vercel

Education

My long-term education goal is to continue learning technology until I am able to create meaningful Economic data applications.

DevMountain / Software Engineering

August 2023 - November 2023 Dallas, Texas JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap, Express, Postgresql

University of North Texas / Bachelor of Science in Economics

August 2004 - December 2008 Denton, Texas

Magna Cum Laude, 3x Dean's List /Econometrics, Statistics, Calculus I & II

PRIOR EXPERIENCE

Before Technology, I worked 10+ years in Financial Services and followed by 4 years in Business Administration Management.

Ultra Packaging - Bilingual Assistant Operations Manager

September 2019 - September 2023 Dallas, Texas

Scottrade - Financial Advisor Representative

January 2009 - March 2018, St.Louis, Denver, Los Angeles

Mentorship

University of North Texas Economics Department / Mentee